<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (C) 2025 Roman Telezhynskyi dismine@gmail.com -->
<component type="desktop">
 <id>ua.com.smart-pattern.valentina.desktop</id>
 <launchable type="desktop-id">ua.com.smart-pattern.valentina.desktop</launchable>
 <name>Valentina</name>
 <summary>Provides a cross-platform patternmaking program which allows designers to create and model patterns of clothing</summary>
 <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
 <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
 <description>
  <p>
   Valentina is a cross-platform patternmaking program which allows designers 
   to create and model patterns of clothing. This software allows pattern 
   creation, using either standard sizing tables or an individual’s set of 
   measurements. It blends new technologies with traditional methods to create 
   a unique pattern making tool.
  </p>
 </description>
 <categories>
  <category>Graphics</category>
 </categories> 
 <url type="homepage">https://smart-pattern.com.ua/valentina/download/</url>
 <url type="bugtracker">https://gitlab.com/smart-pattern/valentina/-/issues</url>
 <url type="translate">https://explore.transifex.com/valentina/valentina-project/</url> 
 <url type="contact">https://smart-pattern.com.ua/contact/</url> 
 <url type="vcs-browser">https://gitlab.com/smart-pattern/valentina</url> 
 <url type="contribute">https://smart-pattern.com.ua/valentina/contribute/</url> 
 <developer_name>Roman Telezhynskyi</developer_name>
 <update_contact>contact@smart-pattern.com.ua</update_contact>
 <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
 <releases>
  <release version="1.1.0" type="development">
    <description>
      <p>
        This is a edge release in the 1.1 series.
      </p>
    </description>
    <issues>
      <issue url="https://gitlab.com/smart-pattern/valentina/-/issues/223">valentina#223</issue>
    </issues>
  </release>
  <release version="1.0.0" type="stable">
    <description>
      <p>
        This is a stable release in the 1.0 series.
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>Fix Puzzle app crash when application closing.</li>
        <li>Dialog Table of variables. Added button Close.</li>
        <li>Fix incorrect seam allowance.</li>
        <li>Duplicate controls for main path nodes.</li>
        <li>Fix compatibility with macOS 12+.</li>
        <li>Fix regression. Formula wizard dialog doesn't show item alias in a list.</li>
        <li>Fix parsing SVG fonts.</li>
        <li>Add "Twin Sans" single stroke font.</li>
        <li>Fixed generation of mirror side of piece based on fold line.</li>
        <li>Puzzle app. Piece rotation with step 15 degrees by holding Ctrl key.</li>
        <li>Fix export of turn points.</li>
        <li>Remove legacy build system.</li>
        <li>Tape and Puzzle crash when check for update.</li>
        <li>Improvements for Windows installer. Automatically install latest Microsoft Visual C++ Redistributable Version if build with MSVC.</li>
        <li>Fix position of fold line.</li>
        <li>Fix an incorrect symmetrical seam line.</li>
        <li>Fix incorrect position of Tape app menu items on Mac OS.</li>
        <li>Change minimal dimension value and minimal step for multisize measurements table.</li>
        <li>Fix a notch on mirror line.</li>
        <li>Fix seam allowance. Prong shape case.</li>
        <li>Added PLT export format as a container for HPGL.</li>
        <li>Fix saving a notch manual angle value.</li>
        <li>Fix creation of invalid variable names.</li>
        <li>Divide the list of export file formats into two.</li>
        <li>Valentina app. Add _1 suffix only when number of sheets bigger than 1.</li>
        <li>Fix orientation of fabric grainline.</li>
        <li>New option Symmetrical copy.</li>
        <li>Renaming a piece name from piece list.</li>
        <li>Tool color picker.</li>
        <li>Valentina app. Added support for drag and drop of pattern files.</li>
        <li>Tape app. Save and restore the column width of a table between sessions.</li>
        <li>Fix boundary together with notches. Case with notch on mirror line.</li>
        <li>Fix applying changes to increments when close the dialog.</li>
        <li>Duplicate a curve inside Seam allowance tool dialog.</li>
        <li>Fix broken seam allowance.</li>
        <li>Added Croatian, Hungarian, Portuguese and Japanese languages.</li>
        <li>Fix incorrect label language in pattern properties.</li>
        <li>Remember last selected manual layout separately from last export path.</li>
        <li>Increase precision for multisize table's dimensions to hold converted values from inches.</li>
        <li>Fix error in VPiece::CuttingPathPoints. It must return full piece path if the piece mirrored.</li>
        <li>Optimize image scaling in database of known measurements.</li>
        <li>Allow user to select another measurements file if current doesn't provide necessary list of measurements.</li>
        <li>Fix calculation of label position for layout piece.</li>
        <li>Tape app. Enable adding multiple images at once.</li>
        <li>Tape app. Adding measurement image in known measurement database by drag and drop.</li>
        <li>Fixed validation of Label language. Missed support for Czech alphabet.</li>
        <li>Incorrect calculation of the intersection point of segments.</li>
        <li>Puzzle app. Export PDF tiles. Make the ruler optional.</li>
        <li>DXF AAMA/ASTM. Compatibility export with Clo3D.</li>
        <li>Puzzle app. Optimization tile PDFs for pen plotter.</li>
        <li>Measurement value alias.</li>
        <li>Sync fold line position to grainline orientation.</li>
        <li>Valentina app. Fix incorrect color of PDF tile's foot notes.</li>
        <li>Improve handling color schema switch on Linux.</li>
        <li>Fix a circular dependency with the CurrentSeamAllowance variable.</li>
      </ul>
    </description>
    <issues>
      <issue url="https://gitlab.com/smart-pattern/valentina/-/issues/223">valentina#223</issue>
    </issues>
  </release>
  <release version="0.7.53" type="development" date="2024-06-25">
      <description>
        <p>
          This is a development release in the 0.7 series.
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix layout sheet export with empty name.</li>
          <li>Fix visualization for tool Point from circle and tangent.</li>
          <li>Fix loading background image.</li>
          <li>Puzzle: message "Invalid version: Max supported version 0.1.2" when opening 0.1.1 file in Val 0.7.52.</li>
          <li>Fix export measurement separator to CSV.</li>
          <li>Fix option Hide labels.</li>
          <li>Improve segmenting a curve for calculating a piece path.</li>
          <li>Fix incorrect seam allowance.</li>
          <li>Export area of piece in Final measurements.</li>
          <li>New option Show accuracy radius.</li> 
          <li>New option Interactive tools.</li>
          <li>Improve error messages while import CSV data.</li>
          <li>Fix regression in dialog Known measurements.</li>
          <li>New option. Default piece label template for new pieces.</li>
          <li>Shortcut to quickly enable/disable Interactive tools mode.</li>
          <li>Improve labels for V notch.</li>
          <li>Fix QT issue on MacOS version 11.0 "Big Sur".</li>
          <li>Fix excluding objects in internal path.</li>
          <li>Fix float-point accuracy issue in multisize measurements dimensions.</li>
          <li>Fix compatibility with Richpeace DXF-AAMA/ASTM R12.</li>
          <li>Fix seam allowance. Loose requirements to case with prong.</li>
          <li>Fix list of dimension popup list. Make sure it will always has enough space for values.</li>
          <li>New grainline type: Four way.</li>
          <li>Show/hide grainline when export.</li>
          <li>Improve calculating notches.</li>
          <li>Simplify number of versions for DXF AAMA/ASTM.</li>
          <li>New notch type - Check Notch.</li>
          <li>Control a notch width and angle with formulas.</li>
          <li>Independent translation for piece labels.</li>
          <li>Piece labels line break.</li>
          <li>Support for single-line fonts.</li>
          <li>Export to HP-GL format.</li>
          <li>Fix crash after using tool Union of details.</li>
          <li>Tool box redesign.</li>
          <li>Increased requirement for minimal Qt version.</li>
          <li>Support for Dark mode.</li>
          <li>Fix issue with passing incorrect number of dimension to Tape.</li>
          <li>New option: Pointer mode.</li>
          <li>Fix GUI freezing while nesting.</li>
          <li>New option: Use Tool Groups.</li>
          <li>Redesign notch context menu to allow quick selection of the notch type.</li>
          <li>Redesign standard path system.</li>
          <li>New option: Translate formula.</li>
          <li>Fix filling piece label data.</li>
          <li>New piece option Follow grainline.</li>
          <li>Validate sheet and layout names before proposing file name.</li>
          <li>Puzzle app. Fix piece position move when update layout data.</li>
          <li>Puzzle app. Fix losing selection by piece.</li>
          <li>Puzzle app. Fix updating layout when file already opened.</li>
          <li>Tape app. Custom measurement name.</li>
          <li>Tape app. Show variables in order they were added.</li>
          <li>Shortcuts manager.</li>
          <li>Support for custom known measurements.</li>
          <li>Allow negative values.</li>
          <li>Tape app. New feature: Always keep on top.</li>
          <li>Label %mFileName% file name punctuation.</li>
          <li>Adding removing nodes of curved path.</li>
          <li>New tools: Arc start point, Arc end point.</li>
          <li>Optimize U-notch shape.</li>
          <li>New feature. Boundary together with notches.</li>
          <li>Puzzle app. Horizontal piece flipping.</li>
          <li>Mirror line.</li>
          <li>Fold line.</li>
          <li>Minimal Qt version increased to Qt 5.15. Minimal C++ standard to C++17.</li>
          <li>Updated Windows installer.</li>
          <li>Automatic crash reports.</li>
          <li>Improve compatibility with Richpeace CAD.</li>
          <li>New warning "Piece gape position".</li>
          <li>New feature. Hide/Show enabled grainline.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
      <issues>
      <issue url="https://gitlab.com/smart-pattern/valentina/-/issues/187">valentina#187</issue>
      <issue url="https://gitlab.com/smart-pattern/valentina/-/issues/189">valentina#189</issue>
      <issue url="https://gitlab.com/smart-pattern/valentina/-/issues/163">valentina#163</issue>
      <issue url="https://gitlab.com/smart-pattern/valentina/-/issues/188">valentina#188</issue>
    </issues>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <release version="0.7.52" type="development" date="2020-09-12">
      <url type="details">https://smart-pattern.com.ua/blog/2022/09/17/release-valentina-0752/</url>
      <description>
        <p>
          This is a development release in the 0.7 series.
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix crash when default locale is ru.</li>
          <li>Puzzle app. Fix incorrect update of a layout piece.</li>
          <li>Fix visualization for tool Point of intersection line and axis.</li>
          <li>Improved curve segment warnings.</li>
          <li>Tape app. Add action Add separator to menu.</li>
          <li>Tape app. Fix crash after switching language.</li>
          <li>Fix Valentina app crash after canceling a tool.</li>
          <li>Puzzle app. Fix reading a piece name.</li>
          <li>Fix warning while segmenting flipped arc.</li>
          <li>Tape app. "Export from existing ..." now supports multisize measurements.</li>
          <li>Fix main path validation. False positive double curve.</li>
          <li>Fix Setup multisize measurements dialog. Improved handling Height dimension.</li>
          <li>Fix updating dimension labels in Valentina app.</li>
          <li>Fix menu on Mac OS X.</li>
          <li>Add function's argument template with name in the Formula Wizard.</li>
          <li>Unit type for increments.</li>
          <li>Support for options Force Flipping and Forbid Flipping in Puzzle.</li>
          <li>Remember selected dimension values.</li>
          <li>Fix segmenting a simple curve.</li>
          <li>Fix export tiled pdf on Mac OS.</li>
          <li>Improve visualization for tools.</li>
          <li>Fix calculating an elliptical arc.</li>
          <li>Enable Approximation scale option for Elliptical arc.</li>
          <li>Fix bug in seam allowance.</li>
          <li>Allow resizing Spline path dialog.</li>
          <li>Improve highlighting file in file browser for Linux.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
 </releases>
</component>
